{
    "id": "4015e778fdf74d50bbf77e075b003ec5",
    "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He asked me what …………………..",
            "description": "In reported questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "was I doing",
                "I was doing",
                "I am doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "70cc26cfb66e4a1293dfa45310b9325a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The stranger enquired where ………………",
            "description": "In reported questions we do not use do, does or did.",
            "answers": [
                "I live",
                "did I live",
                "I lived",
                "do I live"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "129880afd2d14b0cb9eac7136c15d017"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked them ………………… they would listen to such a man.",
            "description": "We can use if or whether to report Yes/No questions.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ca4177bc2e63451796200cbd1dfe81c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The policeman ordered us ……………..",
            "description": "We use infinitives to report imperative sentences.",
            "answers": [
                "that we go away",
                "to go away",
                "go away"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "468d933d22614b82b4c350558fe5d3b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she ..................... me.",
            "description": "Past tenses are used after a past reporting verb.",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't believe",
                "didn't believe",
                "hasn't believed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2d5443675a1f406a9889825d55dc97f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "The king asked the philosopher whom he ………………….. the happiest man living.",
            "description": "Past tenses are used after a past reporting verb.",
            "answers": [
                "consider",
                "considers",
                "considered"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "435eccbb5fb4422a89a5f247dbc04420"
        },
        {
            "question": "I told them …………………",
            "description": "We report imperatives with infinitives. ",
            "answers": [
                "that be quiet",
                "that they be quiet",
                "to be quiet"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "137c3848a12349a58fe09eb7448fbbdf"
        },
        {
            "question": "Alladin asked the magician what ………………….. to deserve such a severe punishment.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "had he done",
                "he had done",
                "he has done"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "21fda95039744549b404d86e7a2497d0"
        },
        {
            "question": "They asked who ..................... and what ……………….",
            "description": "In reported questions, the subject goes before the auxiliary verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are we we want",
                "we were did we want",
                "we were we wanted",
                "were we we wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "04c251721d6e492da7d45ceecda2dd80"
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me to wait until he ……………….",
            "description": "We use past tenses after past reporting verbs.",
            "answers": [
                "came",
                "comes",
                "had come"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "524c8bc66eff429a97e0f512e8b54df1"
        },
        {
            "question": "The king was deeply grieved and asked his wife what ………………….. do for her.",
            "description": "A past reporting verb is followed by verbs in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "could he",
                "he could",
                "he can",
                "can he"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9301d7fe97214a31bbc11055778690fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "He proposed that …………….. wait for the news.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "let them",
                "let him",
                "they should"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "01572c59b26b4e38b35f5fb22526715e"
        }
    ]
}